- If your organization hasn't already adopted
some Agile practices,
I'm sure you've been hearing
about the benefits of moving in this direction.
There are several business imperatives
facing organizations today
and Agile methods can help you attain them.
The most common driver that I hear about
is the need to get software out the door more quickly.
We live in an on-demand world.
The rise of disruptive businesses
and the immediacy of social media
have raised customer expectations.
They demand to get what they want now.
The latest data from the VersionOne
Annual State of Agile Report
reveals that 75% of organizations adopting Agile do so
because they want to accelerate their software delivery.
By another name,
this is something your organization's time-to-market.
Of course you're wondering if that actually happens.
Well, the same dataset reveals that 62% of companies
actually did see improvement in their software delivery
and time-to-market.
Another driver facing businesses today
is related to the one we just talked about.
Given the lightning quick speed of the market
and customer demands,
organizations also need to implement processes
that enable them to quickly respond
to changing requirements.
When companies shift to Agile,
64% of them say they're doing it
because they need a new way to manage changing priorities.
When they do move to Agile, 71% see benefit in this area.
What's interesting here
is the implied impact across their companies
that leads to another benefit of Agile methods.
In order to know what those changing priorities are,
you need to create better alignment
between IT and the business people
who connect you to your customers.
While only 49% of companies listed this as their goal
in their Agile adoption,
a full 65% saw improvement in this area.
Improvement in this alignment
can give you other benefits too.
When there's closer alignment,
all interested parties will have better visibility
into the progress of their projects.
In fact, no one surveyed listed this
as a driver for their adoption.
At the same time, 66% of companies did see this benefit.
Oh, and better visibility generally increases quality
since in short cycles Agile allows your stakeholders
to buy in to what's being delivered.
So, here's the question.
As an IT leader, are you being asked to deliver more
while exactly matching shifting requirements
and bringing your customers along with you while you do it?
If you answered yes, then Agile can help you get there.