- If you've already adopted some agile practices,
are you seeing the great benefits everyone is talking about?
If you're not, I promise you you're not alone.
Agile is not a silver bullet.
It won't solve all your organization's problems for you.
In fact, agile's main strength is exposing the problems
that have been slowing you down all along.
It doesn't solve them, but it shows you what to target.
So when agile fails,
it's showing you a roadmap of things to fix.
Once fixed, these things get out of the way
and you start seeing the results you've been expecting.
So if you're not alone in this, what are others seeing?
Let's look at some of the most common sources
for the problems organizations face.
One root cause for many problems
is simply the lack of training and experience.
In many cases, the introduction of agile is led
by only one or a few people.
These folks learned about it on the internet
and want to give it a try.
There's nothing wrong with that,
and it can be successful for a team or two.
As agile expands beyond that level, though,
you need to invest in training and coaching
to ensure what's being done is done well and sustainably.
Another root cause is your company culture.
Agile is not simply a set of practices.
It's a mindset.
Quite frankly, that mindset tends to run counter
to traditional corporate cultures and philosophies.
Examine your company culture.
Will it be hostile to the agile principles and values?
If it will, agile can only be successful in small pockets
unless you take steps to change your culture.
Next, consider the management team you have in place.
If your transformation isn't well-planned,
this group of leaders will discover on the internet
that in its purest form,
agile has no defined role for managers.
When they see that,
they may work hard to ensure agile doesn't replace them.
Now, you and I both know these leaders are essential
to an organization, agile or not.
As you build your transformation roadmap,
make sure this group is part of it
and has a clearly defined role with training.
Now, consider the tools you have in place
for coding, testing, and deploying.
In many cases, the teams are becoming faster,
but the apparatus for testing and moving code is founded
on waterfall phase gates.
If you want to move to agile at scale,
you'll need to tackle your tools
as part of your transformation roadmap.
Finally, let's talk about metrics.
Agile has a great set of metrics at the team level
that can be consistently applied,
but as you scale to programs and the whole portfolio,
there isn't a comprehensive set of standard metrics.
You'll need to implement this so that you know what to do
to further the transformation.
If any of these things sound familiar,
these may be some of the reasons
you're not seeing the agile benefits you hoped for.
You can make changes to reap the rewards you want.