- There are several approaches
you can take for your transformation.
However, there are critical steps
that must be accomplished,
no matter which approach you choose.
If you miss one or more of those steps,
you'll face challenges in your transformation.
First, you must have a vision
for what you're transforming and why.
This is your call to action
for anyone and everyone
involved in this endeavor.
It becomes your elevator pitch
to all of your stakeholders.
This is the essential first step
in your transformation.
Next, you need to create a team
of individuals who believe in your vision
and are dedicated to getting it done.
It's important to know that this focused
and dedicated team needs to be made up
of the most senior leaders in the organization.
While some tasks and activities
can be delegated to others,
the vision, direction, and momentum
needs to come from the top.
This is your transformation executive board.
Next, you and this core group
will need to build your transformation roadmap.
Some of the things you should
account for in your roadmap include
the organization context for your transformation.
This means you'll need to examine
who will be affected
by the transformation you're planning.
Are these changes restricted
to IT only projects?
Will your business partners be affected?
You need to know the answers to these questions.
Once you know the context,
now you need to understand your customers
and look for partnerships.
I recommend looking at your stakeholders
as either interested or committed.
Are they interested?
Meaning, it may affect them
on projects in the future.
If yes, they just need to be kept in the loop.
If they're committed, you need to ensure
that they're part of the planning and execution.
They should be on your transformation board.
Next, examine how your existing portfolio
will need to change.
In most cases, you've been following
a heavy work intake and tracking process.
This will need to be modified
to get the most out of your transformation.
Then, you'll need to determine
which agile practices you'll implement.
There should be organizational
guardrails on what's being used,
and a consistent framework
for measurement and delivery.
Make sure your roadmap also addresses management.
What is the vision for their role going forward
and how will you train and coach them
to meet those new expectations?
Next, you'll need to tackle
your overall IT organizational structure.
You'll need to answer questions like,
will the hierarchy change,
and will the reporting
and team structures be altered?
Make sure you're addressing technical foundations
throughout your transformation.
You need to make sure that teams
have the right tools to succeed
and space to innovate.
Finally, you'll need to transform your metrics
so you have visibility to your projects,
as well as the health of your transformation.
I know the list of targets
for your transformation is long,
but with some forethought and planning,
you can make it happen.