- When you're preparing to undergo
an IT department transformation,
it's essential to understand who will be affected
by the changes you're introducing.
Identifying these key areas and leaders
can ultimately spell success or failure
for your transformation.
Strictly speaking, everyone in your organization
is a customer of IT.
However, it's helpful to spend some time
identifying your key customer groups
and strategize how your transformation will affect them.
A simple technique to use in identifying
your key stakeholders is to look at data
related to service and support requests.
The goal here is to understand
who the heaviest users of your IT services are.
What's important is knowing their department or area
and getting a rough count of how many requests
or services have been provided.
For example, let's say I'm the CIO
of a large insurance organization.
I've reviewed my service requests for the last two years
and see that most of the requests
come from the claims department,
and the fewest from finance.
Now that I have this data in hand,
I'm going to layer in what I know about my projects
over the last few years.
In this case, I'm looking to identify the departments
or areas that had projects with IT resources
and the relative size of those efforts.
Again, I see that the claims department
has kept us very busy
with three small projects,
four medium size projects,
and one large effort.
Conversely, finance has both
a few large projects and a few small or medium projects.
What this tells me is that I'm going to need
a different engagement strategy for finance
than I use for claims and customer service.
You might be wondering why.
Well, finance doesn't engage with IT very often.
When that's the case,
communications about changes I'm making to processes
will need to repeat over a longer period of time.
When there are infrequent touch points,
I'll have to repeat the information
for a longer period before the changes
become habit to them.
On the other hand, with claims and customer service,
they interact with IT more often,
so the changes will become normal for them fairly quickly.
Now that I know these things,
I can modify my list to identify the leaders
of these organizations.
These are people that I'll go to
and share my plans with.
I'll enlist their help in defining
my communication strategy in their organizations.
In fact, given the frequent interactions,
I'd ask an individual in the claims area
to partner with me on a pilot of my agile transformation.
Agile relies heavily on customer engagement.
Be sure to take these steps to identify
and bring your internal customers with you.
When you do, you'll find the partners you need to succeed.