- While you're transforming your organization,
it's not enough to engage your internal customers.
You also need to leverage your external customers
to ensure you're building the right products.
This is something the IT department
can rarely manage on their own.
This calls for additional deep partnership
with your product development and marketing departments.
Start by understanding how external customers
are currently being engaged.
While there's no standard playbook across all industries
for customer engagement,
some elements are needed universally.
Start by understanding your company's current strategies
in the areas of opportunity assessment
and solution exploration.
In the area of opportunity assessment,
it will be helpful for IT
to understand the process being used
to identify new products or product enhancements.
Your goal is to understand
how external customers are being leveraged.
To maintain market viability, it's critical
that your customers are part of this process.
If it's not already happening,
use your influence to get it started.
Some techniques you can suggest
to your product partners are things
like social media engagement,
webinars to help your customers use your products,
and ask for volunteers to help solve some problem
or design a new product.
With this information and a close partnership
with your product team, IT can help generate ideas
and have early visibility into future projects.
Once opportunities are identified,
you then need to ensure IT is part
of solution exploration as well.
In many cases, the results of opportunity assessment
become projects immediately.
When this happens, all the risk shifts
to the teams doing the work.
Instead, use your partnership with your product team
to insert a solution exploration step into the process.
In this step, you and the product area will form a team
and set a short time box.
The goal is to experiment with prototypes
that will prove or disprove the feasibility
of the opportunity idea.
Make sure you have customer feedback on the prototypes.
This can ensure value in the market as well.
By taking this step,
you now have validated data to work with.
When the new idea for this new product
comes before the project approval team,
it will be a simpler decision
regarding whether or not this opportunity moves forward
and becomes a project.
At this point, you've effectively shared the risk
between IT and product, and done so in a cost-effective
and time-effective manner.
You're investing less up front
in order to justify greater expenditure later.
As an IT leader, engaging your external customers
usually involves other departments in your organization.
Use your influence, and these steps
to create a customer-focused organization.