- In any organization, there are dozens
of requests for projects.
Usually, all the ideas make it
into the portfolio of work
and nothing is ever rejected.
The challenge most organizations face
is assessing the ROI
of these requests quickly and easily.
You'll need to make sure both the business voice
and the technical voice are heard in this effort.
A technique I recommend is the PACE technique.
It's fast, simple and, most importantly,
tells you what not to do.
PACE stands for priority,
action, consider, and eliminate.
This technique places all of the ideas
along this spectrum
and helps you organize
around the most valuable work.
Here's how it works.
First, schedule a prioritization meeting
with your business leadership team.
This group will represent the business voice
and speak strictly to the business value
they see in each idea.
You'll also need your technical leadership team.
This group represents the technical voice
and speaks strictly
to the effort involved
in executing on each idea.
Next, create a numbered list
of your projects or customer needs.
Make sure this list is visible
to all the attendees.
Third, once everyone is in the room,
you'll need to come to an agreement
on what difficult and easy mean
in terms of effort or cost.
This represents the technical voice.
It'll be different for every organization,
but the definitions need to be consistent
for every idea presented in this and future sessions.
For example, you may define easy
to mean one team can complete
the work in one month, or two sprints.
You may decide difficult means
multiple teams are needed
for at least one quarter, or six sprints.
You'll also set the definitions
of high and low on the value scale.
This is the business voice.
For example, you may define low value
as benefiting less than 25% of customers
while high would benefit more than 80%.
Now, you'll create the PACE metrics
on a whiteboard or flip chart.
The X-axis represents the business voice,
and the scale starts with high on the left
and moves to low on the right.
The Y-axis represents the technical voice
and moves from difficult at the bottom
to easy at the top.
Finally, ask the business leaders
to write the numbers representing
the ideas along the X-axis.
The business can't move the number
vertically on the scale, only horizontally,
since they can't speak to the technical
difficulty of the implementation.
Then, ask the technical leaders
to move the numbers
the business has placed on the value line
vertically so that its difficulty
is represented on the cost effort scale.
Finally, add the PACE lines.
The top-left corner is where
your organization should focus.
These have the highest benefit
and will require the least amount of work.
Using the PACE technique,
you can help your business partners
make wise ROI decisions.
Your partnership with the business team
will prove the value of your transforming organization.