- Transforming your organization is more complex
than simply changing processes and practices for your teams.
In order for your transformation to sustain,
you have to change the way work is given to the teams.
In many organizations,
the portfolio of projects or simply your portfolio
is an unwieldy list of all the great business cases
that have accumulated over the years.
It represents projects of varying sizes
and often abstract benefit.
Your first step in getting a handle on the portfolio
is deeply examining everything that's already out there.
This is tactically an easy thing to do
but strategically it's very hard.
That's because for every project in your portfolio,
there's an approved business case
that has one or more people
that's passionate about its delivery.
The first step then
is to start working with these stakeholders.
Your goal is to influence them
and help them see that the status quo is inefficient
and doesn't deliver the value they want quickly enough.
The portfolio hasn't been as nimble
as the business needs it to be.
Once you have their buy-in
to help you critically assess the portfolio,
there are a couple of key steps you can take to get started.
First, gather a list of all the projects in your portfolio
and decide what the shelf life of a business case should be
for your organization.
Yogurt expires and so should your business cases.
This may sound radical but consider this,
the business case is based on a set of assumptions
that were true at that time.
Business and our marketplace changes daily.
A set of assumptions from last year
are not likely to be valid today.
In most cases, if an approved business case
hasn't had work started in one year from its approval date,
it needs to be rewritten and resubmitted.
The assumptions it began with may not be valid anymore.
Don't you want to know whether it's still valid
before work starts?
Of course you do.
Next, you want to ensure that every business case
has stated links to the overall business strategy.
Stakeholders should know
not just the value that the work will deliver to the company
but also that it's aligned
to the long-term business objectives.
Finally, you may have already used PACE
or another method to set the priority of the work
but now you need to compare those high-priority items
against each other.
This is known as sequencing the work.
It helps you understand which high-priority item
should be the first to be executed.
Most companies use the weighted shortest job first
or WSJF for short.
Essentially, WSJF measures the ratio
of the expected business value the work delivers
against the amount of time it will take to deliver it.
It recognizes that items with the highest cost of delay
should be completed first.
As you critically assess your portfolio,
you'll be establishing a flow of work from your business
and through the factory of your Agile teams.
When you do this,
you'll enable your organization for full business agility.