- When you introduce Agile methods at the team level,
you'll definitely see some great benefits.
It won't, however,
solve every problem you're facing as an organization.
Let's take a look at the experience of Elekta
and what happened when they adopted Agile at the team level.
Elekta is a high-tech organization focused on solutions
for treating cancer and brain disorders.
Elekta started by applying Agile, specifically Scrum,
for three teams that were distributed globally.
Each of the teams was working on the same product.
Elekta saw some very real, tangible results.
They experienced increased delivery of work
through their teams and had real,
functioning deliverables each and every Sprint.
They were able to leverage additional agility
at the feature level.
This meant that their business partners
could make smart choices about refining direction
as they learned more.
Elekta also learned that there were still some gaps
that team-level agility couldn't provide.
For example, they realized their teams lost the visibility
across the teams.
While they were delivering quickly and effectively
on their product,
they couldn't see what other teams were doing
and how it all fit together.
In essence, Scrum alone didn't address two key elements.
First, an intake process for all product initiatives
across the portfolio, and second,
a way to coordinate and organize the team's work.
What did Elekta do to solve that?
Well, they set out to better understand the demand
across their product lines and strategic initiatives.
Elekta realized that this understanding
was the foundation to building roadmaps
that can take the organization where it needed to go.
Once they understood the roadmap,
they were able to begin planning the work
and estimating the effort needed to accomplish it.
Elekta created an organization of business
and engineering experts to work together
to complete this high-level analysis and estimation.
The next step, of course,
was to compare what they knew of the estimates
to the capacity the teams actually had.
With this information,
Elekta was able to control the flow of work to the teams.
Further, Elekta was able to accurately forecast
what work would be done when.
This has created an environment where long-term planning
is real and effective.
As you forge your transformation plan,
be sure to include portfolio management changes
into your roadmap.
When you do,
you'll see real benefits for your long-term planning goals.