- As you set out to transform
your organization to agile,
the most important first step
is understanding what it means to be agile
versus simply doing agile.
Executing agile, the actual process
of delivering work though an agile framework,
is fairly simple.
In many cases, companies roll out
the agile techniques and collaboration tools,
and see some improvements.
But they end up unsure
why they're not benefiting
as much as other organizations.
The root cause for this difference is simple;
it's the agile mindset.
Instilling this into your organization
requires a lot of time and effort.
Essentially, you're changing
the culture of your organization.
These cultural changes will help you
reap the rewards you've been hoping for.
So, what is this mindset you need to shift to?
Look at the agile mindset
as a set of foundational values
on which you'll build the organization.
Everyone in your organization
can use them to guide behaviors and habits.
Scrum has a defined set of values
that are a great starting point for every team
and for your organization, as well.
The Scrum values are, first, focus.
Everyone focuses on the work to be done
and the organizational goals.
Next is respect.
Everyone treats all others with respect
and a belief that each person is capable
and are doing the best they can at all times.
Openness.
Team members, leaders, stakeholders.
Everyone agrees to be honest about the work
and the challenges they face.
This is also known as transparency.
Then comes courage.
This value demands that everyone do the right thing
and not shy away from challenges.
This also means that failure
is expected to happen sometimes
and will be faced as a gateway
to greater knowledge.
It also means that everyone
must share their concerns,
so the best solution can be found.
Finally is commitment.
Each person must fully and personally commit
to achieving the goals of the team
and the organization.
When you base your transformation
on a set of values,
you establish expectations
for the future state.
Everyone in the organization,
from the highest to lowest level,
now has a framework from which to make decisions.
Your leadership team needs to model these values
and provide guidance to team members,
so they can live these values, too.
These values then become
foundational expectations
for behaviors that will result
in a high-performing organization.
Once the mindset is in place,
then doing the agile practices
will push your organization forward faster.