- Agile is a broad term
that applies to a family of practice frameworks
that are all based on the Agile Manifesto.
As you can see here, the Agile Manifesto
says it's focused on individuals and interactions.
It really wants to see working software,
and it totally wants the customer included all the time.
This enables us to respond to change.
These are the important tenets of the manifesto.
There are several Agile methodologies,
and we're going to examine the three most popular
and widely-used practices.
Not all practices will be a good fit
for each situation.
So let's take a look at where these might work best.
First, let's talk about Scrum.
Scrum is by far the most common Agile method used.
It's simple, and has been proven
to increase productivity.
In Scrum, the business representative
is part of the team and plays the role
of the product owner, or PO for short.
The PO develops the product backlog
that consists of new features, bug fixes,
and non-functional requirements
like response times.
The PO prioritizes all of the work
the cross-functional team of developers,
analysts, and testers work
to complete the backlog through a series
of two to four week sprints.
Scrum is most commonly used
for software development projects
where ongoing changes are common.
Scrum is a good fit
for distributed teams,
and requires close business collaboration.
This method is designed to handle volatility
in requirements, and high risk efforts.
Next is extreme programming, XP for short.
XP is an increasingly common methodology.
It's a very disciplined, agile approach,
and is focused on delivering software quickly
and continuously.
Where in Scrum, sprints are two to four weeks,
in XP, the cadence is one to three weeks
for the delivery cycle.
XP also demands high customer involvement.
XP focuses on continuous integration of code,
and ongoing testing.
Since the pace is so fast in XP,
it's not ideal for distributed teams.
It also requires a very high,
full-time level of involvement
from your business partners.
Finally, Kanban is a process-oriented Agile practice
that's based on Toyota's Just in Time production model.
The focus here is on eliminating bottlenecks in the system.
Kanban is focused on visualizing your workflow
as you do it today,
then limiting the amount of work in process,
and finally, on enhancing the flow of work
through the system.
Kanban is most often used in process-heavy environments,
especially in the areas of IT support,
where tickets or work requests
flow to a team on a daily,
or even hourly basis.
Generally, the work is flowed through a team
on a first-in first-out basis,
except where priority roles have been established.
As you set out to apply Agile methods
to your organization,
it pays to understand the available frameworks,
and align them to your needs.