- As you embark on transforming your organization to agile,
it's essential to remember that you can't do it alone.
You know that you need to reach out to your business peers
and leaders, but even that isn't enough.
You also need to encourage and foster the transition
within your own leadership team.
The first step in doing this
is to start with those leaders that report to you.
You'll start by sharing your vision with them
and gaining their support.
The next step with this group is to provide them training.
There are different types of training they'll need.
The first type is in the fundamentals of agile.
That includes both the philosophy, or mindset,
and the tactical details of the agile methods
you'll be rolling out.
Another type of training is often forgotten,
and that's role-specific training.
Missing at this item can be disastrous
for your transformation.
We all know that the leaders on your team
will still have their traditional accountabilities
for budget, productivity, and employee engagement.
However, the way in which they execute
on those responsibilities will be different
in an agile organization.
Agile leaders are not task managers
or a directive in how things are accomplished.
Agile leaders rely on establishing goals,
including deadlines, and then inspiring and empowering
their teams to take the lead on the execution of the work.
This is a huge shift for your leaders.
Historically, your team has been successful
at deciding on the path
and directing people to follow their need.
Agile demands leadership from behind,
where the leader is establishing a goal
and creating an environment
where the team members can succeed.
The next level of leadership preparation
is for the next layer down on your organization.
You've gained support for your vision
from your own team members.
Now they need to do the same with their team members.
These leaders will need to follow similar steps
with their team members.
They'll need the same training in the agile mindset,
methodologies, and role-specific guidance
for them to follow.
In my experience, the hardest change to make
is not the tactical implementation of an agile approach.
The hard part is the shifting mindset,
from commanding and controlling,
to enabling and empowering.
In order to create fertile ground for this mindset shift,
you have to start with leadership buy-in
all the way to the top of the organization.
This buy-in communicates that the change is not optional.
Take the time to set the stage for your agile transformation
by engaging and transforming your team.
When you do this, you're taking steps to make sure
agile succeeds for you.