- You may have heard the ongoing debate
about how to approach an agile transformation.
The debate usually centers around
either a top-down approach
or a bottom-up approach.
There is, of course, a third option,
and that's the 360-degree approach.
Let's put the debate to rest
and explore each of these options.
Let's start with the bottom-up approach,
because this happens quite often.
A bottom-up transformation
means exactly what you might infer,
the people at the lowest level of the organization
start the transformation at the team level.
The belief is that team level success alone
will earn buy-in from management.
While this is great,
since it means that you have some innovators
willing to make changes to get better results,
it's also risky to the organization.
For example, if several teams
are running Scrum independently,
there's no overarching goal
or roadmap to the transformation.
It can yield spotty results
without a cohesive vision or plan.
The benefits to be gained will also be limited
when this transformation
bumps into immovable objects,
like release schedules and project phase-gates.
Next, let's talk about the top-down approach.
This approach has the leaders
mandating an agile transformation.
While you need executive buy-in,
forcing teams to do anything
rarely gets you what you're looking for.
Most of the time,
the executives declare the mandate
but are too far removed
from the trenches where the work is done
to see the situation clearly.
In this case, executive expectations
can severely exceed ground-level capabilities.
The risk here is obvious.
When expectations are unrealistic,
any success will be minimized.
Additionally, top-down approaches
tend to occur in the command
and control style of leadership
that an agile mindset is trying to get away from.
Finally, let's explore the 360-degree approach.
This approach, as you might expect,
suggests approaching your transformation
from both the top and the bottom simultaneously.
In my experience, organizations that use
this approach are far more successful
than those using either top-down or bottom-up alone.
In this approach,
you end up with the best of both worlds.
The executive leadership team
is knowledgeable about agile
and is fully supportive of the changes needed.
They're willing to lead the change.
At the same time,
teams by business unit or product
are empowered to explore
the agile methods available to them
and find the one
that most closely suits their needs.
In this way, the team members
can customize where needed,
thus making them more committed
to what's implemented.
Agile transformations can be approached
from more than one angle.
Take the time to understand
which approach will bring you the greatest success.
When you do, your transformation
will yield great results.