- As you begin mapping out your transformation,
you've probably already realized
that the success of your organizational change
is completely dependent on the people in it.
This is true for every organizational change you make.
When you're planning a full transformation,
it pays to engage your human resources team or HR.
Let's take a look at a case study about Volvo
and their realization that HR could have helped them
through the transformation.
At Volvo, the vast majority of employees
are not at the management level.
That being the case, the existing HR frameworks
for communicating with employees can help.
This type of robust communication channel
can spread accurate information.
In the absence of up to date information
about the transition, employee fear and uncertainty grows.
Utilizing HR could have helped Volvo
expand their communication reach.
Another area where HR could have helped Volvo
is in the area of job role mapping.
Volvo shares that HR should be involved
in identifying new roles.
HR is essential in helping leadership
create transition plans for people
to grow into new responsibilities.
As the older structures of the organization
shift to the new agile reality,
HR's help in defining new career paths
can also ease the fears of employees.
Volvo noted that this encouraged employees
to feel safe and valued in the dynamic environment.
Additionally, establishing KPIs for staff
as they transition into their new responsibilities
will also help employees feel safe.
There will be changes needed regarding how team members
are measured and mentored.
Here, HR is an essential partner.
Since HR has a key role in reinforcing company culture
and training policies, it makes sense to include
this aspect of HR in your transformation as well.
Given the reach of HR,
Volvo found that engaging HR to survey staff
during the transformation could provide useful information
engaging the health of the transformation.
Finally, your HR department can help build training
and educational curriculum for existing employees
and new hires.
The material should span both the mindset
and the tactical agile methods you're implementing.
This level of standardized education
will reinforce a cohesive culture in your organization.
Specifically, that means the transition
is happening as a whole, not in silos.
When you take these steps in partnership with HR,
you'll create an agile transformation
that's effective and, most importantly, sustainable.