- As you start your transformation,
you need to take a look
at how your IT department is organized.
Most likely, you're organized
around technical specialties.
For example, you probably have a team
of DBAs with a manager that's a DBA expert.
The same is true for all
the other technical specialties.
When projects arise,
you've probably pulled individuals
from those specialty areas
to form cross-functional teams
until the project is completed.
When you're transitioning
to an agile environment,
all this needs to change.
The speed of agile relies
on establishing cross-functional teams
that stay together, or persist.
These persistent teams need to have
all the skills it takes to deliver software
from concept to cash.
When you create teams like these,
you'll be developing deep
knowledge within those teams.
Deep expertise like this
creates an environment
where innovation can grow.
One manager can handle three
or four cross-functional teams.
The challenge for the manager
is to recognize that they're no longer
the expert and problem solver for the team.
Their role shifts to one of support,
mentoring, coaching, and issue resolution.
They're empowering the teams
to solve technical problems themselves.
Are they still a technical resource for the team?
Of course they are.
But their role isn't to provide answers,
it's to ask the questions
in a way that pushes the team
to find the best solutions themselves.
I realize it can be overwhelming to think
about reorganizing the whole IT department.
One of the best tools you can use to help you
is a value stream map.
This is a lean management tool
that helps you visualize
the steps a product takes
as it goes from concept through development
and release to your customers' hands.
Don't try to value stream map your whole department;
just pick one product or application to start with.
You can then systematically
target other products and applications.
Your goal is to truly understand
how things currently exist.
You need to understand how the work passes
between teams and individuals.
It's really critical that this mapping effort
is done by talking to people in your department.
You can't rely on documentation that already exists.
Why?
Well, over time, documented procedures
are treated as guidelines.
That means that team members
have been modifying the guideline
with their actual behavior.
They do this not to circumvent policy or procedure,
but simply to make it more useful in the real world.
Since your goal is to understand the reality,
talking to people is the best way
to get what you need.
With this information, you'll begin to see
what skills are needed on your cross-functional teams
to get product out the door.
You can then visualize
what your reorganized department could look like.
When you're starting to transform,
these steps can help you
create a vision for the future.