- As organizations transition to adopting
more agile frameworks, they run into challenges.
The concept of scaling agile comes from the need
to resolve these issues.
Scaling is simply a shorthand way of saying
you're expanding the footprint of agile in the organization.
Think of scaling in terms of which teams
or groups of teams have adopted the agile mindset
and practices.
For example, the simplest way to scale agile
is for multiple teams to adopt agile.
Usually, this is done within a product.
For example, if you're working at Amazon,
you may have more than one team
working on the private wishlist feature.
When all the teams working on private wishlists
are using agile, you've scaled agile to that product.
Then, you may see how well this is working
and decide that all teams on the list platform
should use agile practices too.
This is scaling the platform.
Both of these examples are focused on product delivery.
You can also scale or expand your agile
at the organizational level.
For example, if I were leading an IT department,
I could choose to use agile throughout my whole area.
This is organizational scaling.
All the teams in my area would transform
to the agile mindset and frameworks.
I could then help my peer leaders
to see the benefit of agile
and influence them to scale their departments too.
When those other areas start to adopt agile,
this is enterprise scaling.
It means that the agile mindset and practices
are used everywhere in my company.
It helps to understand that scaling
isn't a single thing.
It has many facets, and you can choose how
and where to start.
When you know this, you'll make the right decision
for your organization.