- Before setting out to scale,
you need to consider the pros and cons of the models.
Let's look at the Spotify model and why ING Bank chose it.
This model is named after the company
that created the model, Spotify.
Based on the Scrum methodology,
in this model the work is done by Agile teams
known as squads.
At ING Bank, each squad is highly autonomous,
focused on a single client-related activity
and has no more than nine members.
It's also interesting to note
that these squads include business expertise
like marketing and product management along with IT members.
In order to handle coordination across the squads,
tribes of squads are formed.
Tribes then are what you'd find traditionally
at the program level.
Tribes coordinate priorities,
budgets and interact with other tribes
when there are dependencies.
In order to maintain technical consistency within a tribe,
chapters are formed to define and ensure best practices.
For example, .NET developers from squads within a tribe
would form a chapter to ensure all teams were coding
to architectural guidelines.
Guilds are formed for the same purpose.
The only difference is that guilds form
across multiple tribes.
ING Bank chose the Spotify model for several reasons.
Key among those reasons are it's focused
on minimizing barriers to agility like bureaucracy.
It empowers individuals and provides autonomy to teams.
And most importantly, centering the squads around single,
customer-focused objectives
truly made it a customer-centered organization.
What are the results of their choice?
ING Bank has dramatically improved their time-to-market
and has become the primary mobile bank in the Netherlands.
Now let's look at the pros and cons of the Spotify model
to help you get started with your decision.
One of the pros for using Spotify
are the cross-functional teams.
The squads can handle the whole development lifecycle
and put the product into customer hands.
It's designed to do all of these things quickly
and with high quality.
Given the squad-tribe-chapter-guild structure,
Spotify is highly focused
on maintaining architectural integrity
and high coding standards across the whole organization.
This is another pro for using Spotify.
On the con side, this model is product focused.
That means that if you have fixed schedule releases
where there are external date pressures,
this model may not fit well for you.
Further at the portfolio level,
there is no prescribed format for work management
and prioritization before it flows to the teams.
There is an assumption
that a healthy product management organization
is in place to handle these aspects.
Additionally, dependency management is handled informally
at the tribe level and may not provide the level of rigor
you're looking for.
No matter which model you choose,
make sure you're crystal clear
on the objectives you hope to attain.
With this foremost in your mind,
you'll choose the right framework for you.