- We know there are several scaling models out there.
Let's take a look at the Scaled Agile Framework,
SAFe for short, and why an arm of the US Government,
Fannie Mae has chosen it.
Fannie Mae is the largest provider
of mortgage financing in the US.
After the housing crisis in 2013,
Fannie Mae recognized that it needed to be more responsive
to changing customer demands.
The SAFe model is all about alignment and collaboration
across large numbers of Agile teams.
It relies heavily on Agile software development,
Lean product management and systems thinking.
SAFe has Scrum or Kanban teams
at the foundation of the model.
Groups of teams working together at the program level
are formed into Agile Release Trains or ARTs.
All the teams within an ART collaborate
around a product increment or PI.
In SAFe, the PIs are on a cadence
or schedule that releases in unison.
Usually the PI is three months or a quarter in length.
At the portfolio level, SAFe has created a detailed model
around how organizations can select
the right work to complete.
It also helps sequence the order
of the work flowing into an ART.
Work is funneled to the ARTs
from the portfolio management team
that approves work based on organizational objectives.
Then related work items are sequenced
to create product increments.
Fannie Mae chose the SAFe model
because it focuses on continuous
integration and early testing.
Adopting Agile and SAFe allowed them to mitigate risk.
Fannie Mae has seen a couple of results.
Reduced risk through their focus
on automation and continuous integration.
Dramatically improved quality
as evidenced by significantly reduced defect rates.
Let's look at the pros and cons of the SAFe model
to help you get started with your decision.
On the pro side this is the most
popular scaling model out there.
Since it's so prevalent it's easy
for an organization to find the training
and coaching they need to support their roll out.
SAFe even provides a detailed roadmap
telling you how to implement it.
SAFe is well suited to large organizations
and emphasizes establishing teams
that stay together for a long time.
On the con side of SAFe.
First, since you're being told
what to do to roll it out
you don't have to have deep organizational
understanding of why you're doing it.
If you're looking for that Agile mindset culture change,
SAFe might not deliver.
This is a highly prescriptive model,
you need a lot of training
throughout the whole organization.
People criticize SAFe for pushing training
and certification as a revenue model,
and because access to information can be restricted,
you have to be a member of the SAFe community
to get all the details.
Speaking of which, to learn the SAFe framework
you'll want to go to their website for additional details.
But don't make your decision based
on these characteristics alone.
The pros and cons of scaling models
only make sense when assessed
against your organization's needs.