- All models for scaling have advantages and drawbacks,
but we need to align those
with our own organization's objectives.
Let's look at JPMorgan Chase and their experience
with the Large-Scale Scrum or LeSS model.
In 2013, the global core processing technology organization
decided to transform to scrum and the LeSS model.
They started in the securities department
to prove the model out.
The LeSS model is focused entirely
on spreading the scrum framework
across the whole organization.
Specifically, the model tries to remove levels
from the organization, thus eliminating complexity
and increasing speed, quality, clarity, and collaboration.
There are two levels of LeSS.
The first level, LeSS, is designed for up to eight teams,
and the second, called LeSS Huge,
scales to greater than 1,000 developers.
The model itself is quite straightforward
since it takes the scrum framework used on a single team
and applies it to multiple teams.
The LeSS version or multi-team scrum is organized
around products or services.
Each product or service then has a single backlog,
and multiple teams pull from that backlog.
When JPMorgan Chase set out to improve their scrum rollout,
they chose to go with LeSS
because they wanted to eliminate bureaucracy
in the organization that hinders agility
and implement coordinated teams to reduce handoffs,
dependencies, and delays in getting products to market.
What results has Chase experienced?
Well, they've seen great reductions
in handoffs and context switching.
These have had direct bottom-line benefits
to reducing waste and delays.
They've also seen improved transparency and speed
since the teams are empowered
to make many decisions by themselves.
Let's look at the pros and cons of the LeSS model
to help you get started with your decision.
As a pro, since it's based on scrum,
LeSS is easy to understand and apply.
This model is highly configurable
to the needs of your organization.
Here the focus is really on creating working product
and minimizing organizational overhead.
In most cases, this means that the org chart
will change dramatically.
LeSS calls for the creation of product-focused,
customer-centric teams that stay together for a long time.
At the program level,
dependencies are handled through solid DevOps practices,
sharing code bases, and doing frequent code integrations.
At the portfolio level,
LeSS expects a robust product management organization
to prioritize and plan out the features
before they reach the teams.
The biggest con with LeSS is the high level
of discipline you must instill in the organization
in the actual practice of scrum.
Since this is the least prescriptive method
that's commonly used,
you'll have to solve for some gaps with customization.
Another challenge with this model is
that it necessitates a complete change
in your IT organizational structure.
If LeSS is the way you want to go, that's great,
but you're going to have to know
that this model requires a wholesale commitment.
Be sure you decide
in accordance with the state of your organization.