- In many organizations I've worked with,
IT architects have been resistant to Agile.
Usually, they believe that the teams
will be designing solutions for their product
in a silo and won't take the larger ecosystem into account.
In fact, Agile demands that the teams
ground their development
within the context of the organization as a whole.
The architectural framework and standards
will apply to the teams and their solutions
throughout the product life cycle.
At the same time,
the Agile approach is different
from the Waterfall approach.
In the Waterfall method, all the design is done upfront.
Development becomes something like a paint-by-numbers,
where a code is written to the upfront specs.
When new information is discovered
that could change the design,
the developer has to go back
and get approval for the change.
The Agile architecture approach is different.
It acknowledges the complexity inherent in large systems
and large solutions.
It expects teams to exist in an ecosystem
that has been deliberately established.
From there, Agile expects teams to make design solutions
for their product.
That means the team is responsible for staying within
the established ecosystem,
while designing the best solution they can
for their product.
Product-specific designs are expected to emerge
from the team doing the work.
This emergent design is meant to fit within
the deliberate architectural framework.
Further, Agile expects teams and architects
to work collaboratively.
The architects that are responsible for the solution
and enterprise frameworks
need to understand what's happening at the team level.
As the team continues developing and discovering
and designing, the architects need to partner with them.
The partnership will ensure the ecosystem
supports the design and the design supports the ecosystem.
Without this level of collaboration,
you run the risk of either returning to big, upfront design
or having teams produce code that doesn't work
in your ecosystem.
To ensure you have this level of partnership in place
in your organization,
make sure that both your developers and architects
are trained on Agile practices.
Additionally, make sure they understand and are trained
on Agile architecture specifically.
Enable the two groups to define the best way
for all of them to maintain visibility and alignment
throughout the product life cycle.
When you take these steps,
you'll ensure the architecture in your organization
is both agile and stable.