- You can transform your organization to agile practices
without implementing any changes
to the underlying systems and processes teams use.
These underlying structures
are the things that teams use to test and deploy code
into the production environment.
Transforming to agile
without implementing any changes in this area though
will limit the benefits you see from your transformation.
You might wonder why that is.
So let's explore it for a minute.
Your teams will be doing agile development.
That means they'll be following Scrum, XP,
or any of the other frameworks.
Teams will unlock the advantages of speed and quality
that come with that change.
However, organizational agility is something else entirely,
and that's what DevOps provides.
DevOps is the practice of partnership
between software development and operations engineers
throughout the entire value stream.
From design all the way through production support
for the products being released,
the engineers work together
to ensure the quality and stability of the product.
DevOps focuses on automating the processes
between software development teams
and IT infrastructure teams.
The goal is to build, test, and release software
faster and more consistently.
As a whole, the DevOps movement
applies the agile principles and mindset
to the practice of releasing and supporting
the deployed solution.
DevOps seeks tighter integration
between software and operations.
It's a framework then for continuous delivery,
continuous integration, and automated testing.
I have worked with organizations that transformed to agile
without having a plan or a roadmap in place
for DevOps transformation.
The result of these transformations
was only partially successful.
This is because all they did
was to push the barriers to agility downstream.
What I mean by this
is that before those organizations adopted agile,
the teams were slow and couldn't produce products
fast enough in the traditional environment.
Agile methods provided
the fast development lifecycle they needed.
However, when they didn't improve the ways
the teams tested and released code,
the system remained just as slow as they were before.
Now the bottleneck for delivery is no longer the team.
It's the infrastructure supporting them.
As you plan out your agile transformation,
take the time to include DevOps changes into your plan.
To help you get started,
check out the LinkedIn learning course
DevOps Foundations: Lean and Agile.
When you do, you'll be on your way
to full organizational agility.