- Organizational silos are common.
In fact, they're everywhere.
Silos generally develop to solve very specific problems.
When specialized knowledge or skill is needed,
you build a group of specialists to tackle the problems.
These groups then become silos of knowledge and skill.
When you look at a typical IT department,
the organizational structure is a series of silos.
For example, you usually see divisions along specialty.
Software development may be one of your silos.
Even that can be subdivided into further silos
like .NET or Java.
While it's good to have the breadth and depth of knowledge
to effectively run your organization,
it can cause problems.
The problems are probably ones you're already seeing
in your organization.
Namely, information isn't shared freely.
Each knowledge area has their own
key performance indicators, or KPIs,
and many times they conflict with each other.
For example, the software development silo
may have KPIs related to the frequency
of new software deployments.
That KPI may demand frequent release of code.
At the same time, the testing silo may have KPIs
related to the number of defects found in code
before it's released.
This push/pull in your department
can cause conflict between the silos.
That conflict distracts everyone
from focusing on the mission.
As you move through your agile journey
you'll need to address the silos in your organization.
Creating cross-functional teams
and getting started on DevOps will help.
There is still more to do, though.
You may have already heard the term networked organization,
and that's really what you'll need to do
so that all of IT is directed toward the common goal.
A networked organization is simply one that understands
that the knowledge silos, or clusters,
are necessary, and, in fact, vital.
Further, it focuses on connecting the clusters
as closely as possible.
This is known at the path length.
Your goal then is to strengthen the skills in the clusters
while finding ways to keep the path links
between the clusters short.
There are simple steps you can take
to foster networking in your organization.
First, I suggest implementing
an onboarding program within IT.
You'll want the program to include cross cluster members
in each class.
Further, you can have mid and senior employees
lead the program.
This will encourage mentor/mentee relationships.
In the end, your new employees
will have the informal networks needed
to shorten the path links.
As you transform your organization,
remember silos aren't your enemy.
You can leverage them
and start networking your organization.