- When you launched the organization on the path
of IT transformation, you had some goals to accomplish.
These goals are a great place to start
when deciding what to measure.
In my experience, the most common goals
for agile implementations are faster delivery,
or speed, and higher quality.
Let's start by looking at faster delivery.
When measuring speed, the easiest way to measure
is simply capturing the number of deliveries each month.
This is an external measure that helps you understand
how your transformation
is directly impacting your external customers.
An additional metric to start tracking
is lead time for the work being done.
Tracking lead time, or the duration
between the request and the delivery,
is an internal speed metric.
This can provide valuable insight
into the efficiencies being created in the organization
as you implement agility.
In terms of quality, the most direct measure
is defect tracking.
I recommend teams track their own defects,
and these can then be combined across teams
to provide a broader view.
When tracking defects, I find it useful
to know how many defects the team found during development.
Most importantly, it's best to track
the number of defects found after the release
or found by customers.
These defect trends can provide visibility
on how your transformation is improving
the end product customers experience.
Another area to track during your transformation
is the cultural aspect.
Agile can't take hold unless your culture is changing too.
Agile relies heavily on collaboration
and team empowerment.
A simple pulse survey to your IT staff
can provide transparency on both fronts.
For example, you can ask simple questions like:
On a scale from one to 10
where one is low and 10 is high,
how healthy is collaboration within your team?
This question can tell you
how well the transformation is working
at the team level.
On a scale from one to 10
where one is low and 10 is high,
how healthy is collaboration across teams?
This question provides visibility
into the health of the system
or the team of teams.
On a scale from one to 10
where one is low and 10 is high,
how autonomous is your team?
This question really provides information
on where the transformation stands
in terms of empowering teams.
This is the foundation for high performance.
In all cases, make sure you baseline measurements
before your transformation begins.
It's much easier to tell the story
of your agile success when you know where you started.
When you choose the right metrics,
you'll be able to keep your transformation on track
and share the good news.