- As you establish your agile teams,
you'll want to start measuring
their growth in agile practices.
This can help you understand where there are areas
you should provide additional training
or support to the teams.
Almost all teams track their velocity metric.
For our purpose of understanding how agile
or healthy a team is, this metric is not useful.
While it's a great tool for the team to use
and self assess, since point measures vary by team,
they aren't useful when you're looking
across the department.
There are a few metrics I recommend using.
First, measure team size.
Any team with fewer than three people
or more than 10 people is going to be less efficient
than teams sized between four and 10.
When a team falls outside these parameters,
it's time to look into the situation and try to remedy it.
This is an ongoing measure and should be looked at monthly.
Also related to this is a measurement
of team member dedication.
While complete dedication to a single team
is the ideal state, it may not be possible for every team.
Measure this and try to ensure that fewer than 30%
of team members are working on more than one team.
Next, capture the ratio of committed
to completed story points for each sprint.
This measure gauges the team's ability to plan effectively.
The goal is for the team to hit their commitment
within 10%, plus or minus.
For example, if a team committed 20 points
and completed 18, they're within their goal.
This you'll want to measure every four sprints or so.
The expectation is that the team usually hits their metric.
If the trend shows continuous large misses,
you'll want to investigate further
and help the team with additional coaching or training.
Next, release frequency is a good metric of team agility.
This will tell you whether working software
is being released to production after each sprint.
If it isn't happening, it will tell you
how long releases are actually taking.
Again, this metric will indicate whether the team
has the environment they need to release.
Additionally, it can provide insight
into what the product owners are deciding
as being valuable to release.
Both are good areas for investigation and collaboration.
Finally, technical excellence is a great metric to track.
This is captured by understanding how many defects
are found by the team during development,
by others outside the team, and by customers.
When you start to measure team agility,
you'll start to see patterns across the organization.
For example, if all teams have high numbers of defects
that are found by customers, it's an opportunity
for you to take action and help the teams improve
with education or tools.
You don't need to measure all of these things,
but be sure to select at least a few items.
What you do measure should be related to the goals
you set for your transformation.
When you measure your team's agility,
you'll gain valuable insight
into the health of your transformation.