- We know that an Agile transformation
will impact every area of the organization.
You'll be applying metrics
at the team and organization level
to see the health of the transformation.
The portfolio is the entry point
for work moving to the teams.
Assessing the well-being of the portfolio transformation
is a key element.
What should you be looking for?
Well, there are many measures you can use.
For me, there are four key measures that I look for.
First, I like to measure strategic alignment.
Every company has strategic objectives they try to attain.
These objectives are linked to the company's mission.
Therefore, all work being done should be directly linked
to attaining one of those objectives.
This is a straightforward tracking item.
Each feature or work item that's in the portfolio backlog
or is actively being worked
should tie to at least one of the objectives.
If something isn't linked,
it's an invitation to assess
whether the feature should be killed
or transformed into something with alignment.
Next, it's a great idea to measure investment class targets.
When budgets are created,
they're usually divided into categories of work.
I use the run, grow, and transform classes.
Run features are related
to keeping the business going as is.
Grow features are those that will expand the footprint
of existing products and services.
Transform features are related to creating
completely new products or services.
It's likely that your budgets reflect these classes.
Keep tabs on the work that is active
or planned in your portfolio
to ensure work is aligned to established investment classes.
Third, I like to keep track
of the overall efficiency of the system
by capturing a cycle time metric.
This measures how long it takes
for a feature to be completed once work starts.
The goal is to keep cycle time as low as possible
without having a negative impact on quality.
Finally, related to quality
is a measurement of business value.
For this, I use a Net Promoter Score, or NPS.
An NPS measures customer loyalty to your brand.
This is known as the relationship score.
Another type of NPS measures a customer's experience
with a specific transaction.
In this case,
if you've released a new feature
and want to gauge the customer experience with it,
you can use an NPS transactional survey
to gain insight into the value being delivered.
This can be used with both internal and external customers.
As you measure the transformation against your goals,
you'll gain valuable insight
into where you may need to shift your focus.
Keeping track of your portfolio health
will help you ensure you're delivering what's needed.