- Undertaking an agile transformation is a huge effort.
It will take all of your skill
to move the organization forward.
Remember no organization's transformation is like any other.
Each is as unique as your company.
Agile is intended to be tweaked, to perfectly fit your needs
and it's intended to evolve as
your organization grows and changes.
As long as you remain grounded in the agile mindset,
you'll be just fine.
Thank you for spending time with me
as we examine all of the changes
that will need to take place.
To help you continue on your transformation journey,
I recommend you read the following books.
First, 'Turn the Ship Around' by David Marquet.
This is an inspiring story of transformation
on a nuclear submarine.
'Value Stream Mapping' by Karen Martin and Mike Osterling,
which will help you identify and understand
your IT organization as a group of value streams.
Finally if you want a deeper look at DevOps,
I suggest you read 'Leading the Transformation'
by Gary Gruver and Tommy Mauser.
If you haven't already, it might be a good time
to find an agile coach you can partner with
to roadmap your transformation.
Thank you so much for taking this deep dive
into agile transformation with me.
Please reach out to me on LinkedIn.
I'd love to hear from you
and learn about your transformation questions.
Good luck to you and your teams.