- Agile transformations are happening everywhere these days.
The problem is that some are more successful than others.
In this course you'll learn the essential ingredients
to successful agile transformations,
and you'll be able to apply them in your organization.
We'll use case studies to learn how
successfully transformed organizations
used these techniques,
and we'll also look at the pros and cons
of the scaling frameworks.
If you're starting a transformation journey,
these key steps will help you succeed in your efforts.
Hi, I'm Kelley O'Connell.
I'm an agile coach and transformation strategist.
I have been leading teams for more than 20 years,
and I've been involved with transforming organizations
for 10 years.
Please join me as we explore how you
can successfully transform your organization.