- Your situation and organization will be unique.
This course takes a very tactical approach
to what steps are required
even if their timing is different across organizations.
We'll deepen your understanding
of what it takes to transform to agile.
We'll explore both the frameworks and the needed mindset.
If you're new to agile, I recommend taking my course
on Transitioning from Waterfall to Agile Project Management.
Many organizations have already made some progress
introducing agile methods to their organizations.
But, you may be unsure why you haven't seen
the results you hoped for.
We'll explore why this may be happening for you.
From there, we'll start looking at a more holistic view
of an agile transformation.
We'll probe the allies you'll need to bring on your journey.
We'll also discuss measurements that can provide you
visibility into how your own transformation is going.
If you're ready for a deep tactical examination
of transitioning to agile, this is the course for you.
Let's get started.